You've probably heard that you should
always negotiate your salary. But, what
happens when your employer or potential
employer denies a raise? Ron Seifer,
Korn Ferry's North America Reward and
Benefits Leader, says that new hires or
current employees should always follow
up with two [music] questions if their
request for a raise gets denied. The
first question is, "How does the
organization make compensation decisions
for this role?" The candidate can be
more specific by asking [music] whether
the company considers market data,
internal equity, performance, scope of
responsibility, and timing in its
decision-making. Seifer says that the
goal of this question is to better
understand the company's compensation
philosophy and decision criteria. And,
he said that well-managed organizations
should be able [music] to explain their
pay decisions. The second question to
ask is, "What would need to be true for
my compensation [music]
to be revisited, and when can we agree
to revisit it?" The candidate should ask
about specific outcomes, expanded
responsibilities, performance
milestones, and market changes [music]
that would lead to revisiting the
discussion. Seifer says that that
question gives the candidate or employee
a clear set [music] of expectations, and
both them and the employer a natural way
to reopen [music] the conversation. To
read more about negotiation strategies,
head to Business Insider.